# **Daniel Letson**

daniel.letson@gmail.com daniel-letson.com

### Objective

I design digital products with integrity, based on a user-centered research process and 10+ years of experience building both on the web and IRL. I specialize in simple, scalable designs with a keen eye for detail and a knack for non-standard solutions.

### Education

203.470.2639

Carnegie Mellon BFA, Industrial Design

> Magna Cum Laude Spring 2008

# **Proficiencies**

User Experience Design
User Research
Web Accessibility
Data Visualization
Market Research
Information Architecture
UX Writing
Agile Development

Figma Adobe CC Affinity Photo/Designer

> HTML5 / CSS3 JS / ECMAScript Node / NPM ReactJS D3JS Git

### **Experience**

Fluxx Labs · Senior Product Designer · 2019 - Present

Directed product design efforts for a leading SaaS platform for nonprofits. Brought a B2C product from free beta to paid subscription model, achieving profitability within 6 months. Launched 16 major features to over 30k users at many of the most prominent organizations in US philanthropy. Built the company's first UI design system, owned web analytics for the platform, and mentored a junior designer for 2 years.

### Turnitin · Web Lead, Marketing · 2013 - 2019

Managed design, planning, and development tasks for the global marketing team of a major Ed-Tech platform. Redesigned and developed the company's flagship marketing website, with millions of monthly visitors across 12 regional sites. Single-handedly built a new CMS and migrated more than 300 pages to a new infrastructure. Launched the company's first data-driven marketing campaign, built bespoke data analysis tools for salespeople, and managed a visual designer for 3 years.

### Klassik Living · Design Contractor · 2010 - 2013

Served as a jack-of-all-trades contractor for an upscale reseller of vintage Danish modern furniture — refinishing and repair, merchandising, product photography, and web marketing.

#### Zarganis, Inc · Woodworker · 2008 - 2010

Designed, engineered, and fabricated custom furniture and architectural elements, incorporating reused materials and green technologies, including work on a LEED Platinum Certified office suite.

#### CREATE Labs · Product Designer · 2007

Designed and prototyped interactive robotic devices alongside a team of engineers and educators. Developed curricula, organized events, and conducted user testing workshops.

# Volunteering

Internet Archive · Web Developer · 2016

Built templates and new functionality for the Political Ad Archive in the run up to the 2016 general election.

### KALX Berkeley · Music Director · 2014 - 2016

Organized student and community volunteers, sourced music, wrote newsletters, and liaised with music industry representatives on behalf of one of the most venerable freeform radio stations in the country.